{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. For a simple pendulum the time period of one oscillation is given by",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2 π √(g/l)",
        "b": "2 π √(2l/g)",
        "c": "2 √(l/2g)",
        "d": "2 π √(l/g)"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    
    {
      "question": "2. In order to double the period of a simple pendulum, the length of the string should be",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Halved",
        "b": "Doubled",
        "c": "Quadrupled",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. For a linear time invariant system, an optimal controller can be designed if",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The system is controllable and observable",
        "b": "The system is uncontrollable but stable",
        "c": "The system is unstable but observable",
        "d": "The system is stable but unobservable"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Calculate the frequency of a pendulum oscillating 80 times in 8 seconds",
      "answers": {
        "a": "8 Hz",
        "b": "1/8 Hz",
        "c": "10 Hz",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "5. A slow running pendulum clock can be speeded up by,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increasing the length of the rod",
        "b": "Increasing the weight of the bob",
        "c": "Reducing the length of the rod",
        "d": "Reducing the weight of the bob"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },	
	
	{
      "question": "6. If a clock, based on oscillating pendulum is taken to the moon, it will",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Become slow",
        "b": "Become fast",
        "c": "Gives same time as on the earth",
        "d": "Stop working"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "7. Which of the following variables has zero value at the extreme position in simple harmonic motion ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Acceleration",
        "b": "Speed",
        "c": "Displacement",
        "d": "Angular frequency"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	
	{
      "question": "8. The period of simple pendulum inside the satellite orbiting earth is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Zero",
        "b": "2T",
        "c": "T",
        "d": "Infinite"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "9. The mass of the bob is made one fourth of a simple pendulum having time period T, then its time period will be",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2T",
        "b": "4T",
        "c": "0.707T",
        "d": "T"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "10. A simple pendulum completes 40 oscillations in 64 sec. What is the time period of the pendulum?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.625",
        "b": "6",
        "c": "1.6",
        "d": "16"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
	
  ]
}

